<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title><![CDATA[Machine Learning - Deep Neural Notebooks]]></title><description><![CDATA[Deep Learning Stories | Productivity | Learning]]></description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><image><url>http://localhost:2368/favicon.png</url><title>Machine Learning - Deep Neural Notebooks</title><link>http://localhost:2368/</link></image><generator>Ghost 3.21</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 03:30:46 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/tag/machine-learning/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[DNN 9: Computer Vision & ML Inside The Car, NVIDIA's AI Co-Pilot // Shalini De Mello]]></title><description><![CDATA[<figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><iframe width="100%" height="232" allowtransparency="true" frameborder="0" allow="encrypted-media" title="Spotify Embed: DNN 9: Computer Vision &amp; Machine Learning Inside The Car, NVIDIA's AI Co-Pilot | Shalini De Mello, Research Lead, NVIDIA" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed-podcast/episode/0E6wVlJTTnu2qolksBHRLs"></iframe></figure><p>In this episode, I talk with Shalini De Mello, who is a Principal Research Scientist and Research Lead at NVIDIA. Her research interests are in computer vision and machine learning for human-computer interaction and smart interfaces.</p><p>At NVIDIA, she has developed technologies for gaze estimation, 2D and 3D head pose</p>]]></description><link>http://localhost:2368/dnn-9-computer-vision-machine-learning-inside-the-car/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5f0805899305f6020934745b</guid><category><![CDATA[Computer Vision]]></category><category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category><category><![CDATA[Human Computer Interaction]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Mukul Khanna]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 06:09:29 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2020/07/Podcast-thumbnails.010.jpeg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><iframe width="100%" height="232" allowtransparency="true" frameborder="0" allow="encrypted-media" title="Spotify Embed: DNN 9: Computer Vision &amp; Machine Learning Inside The Car, NVIDIA's AI Co-Pilot | Shalini De Mello, Research Lead, NVIDIA" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed-podcast/episode/0E6wVlJTTnu2qolksBHRLs"></iframe></figure><img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2020/07/Podcast-thumbnails.010.jpeg" alt="DNN 9: Computer Vision & ML Inside The Car, NVIDIA's AI Co-Pilot // Shalini De Mello"><p>In this episode, I talk with Shalini De Mello, who is a Principal Research Scientist and Research Lead at NVIDIA. Her research interests are in computer vision and machine learning for human-computer interaction and smart interfaces.</p><p>At NVIDIA, she has developed technologies for gaze estimation, 2D and 3D head pose estimation, hand gesture recognition, face detection, video stabilization and GPU-optimized libraries for mobile computer vision. Her research has been focused on human-computer interaction in cars and has led to the development of NVIDIA’s innovative DriveIX product for smart AI-based automotive interfaces for future generations of cars.</p><p>Shalini received her Masters and PhD in Electrical and Computer Engineering from the University of Texas at Austin. She received a Bachelor of Engineering degree in Electronics and Electrical Communication Engineering from Punjab Engineering College.</p><p>In this episode, we talk about her journey - about how she got started with Computer Vision and Machine Learning, from her Bahelor's to her Master's in BiomedicaliImaging to her PhD work on Human Face Recognition - about how her research interests shaped over the years. We also talk about Machine Learning inside the car, about her vision of using Machine Learning &amp; Deep Learning for building smart assistive interfaces for inside the car, and about how that manifested into the DriveIX product that NVIDIA recently launched. Among other things, we talk about the importance of open-sourcing technology, about the future of autonomous and semi-autonomous vehicles, about the joys of learning something new everyday, about how to keep track of the every growing amount of research and much more.</p><p>It was an absolute pleasure to talk with Shalini and learn from her research insights. I hope you like the conversation.</p><p>Links: <a href="https://youtu.be/Hfz965mLuvM">Youtube</a> / <a href="https://tinyurl.com/ya98vk7b">Anchor.fm</a> / <a href="https://tinyurl.com/y9hu7lzq">Apple Podcasts</a> / <a href="https://tinyurl.com/yb6sn2rv">Spotify</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[DNN 8: Computer Vision & ML Research, Super SloMo // Varun Jampani]]></title><description><![CDATA[<figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><iframe width="100%" height="232" allowtransparency="true" frameborder="0" allow="encrypted-media" title="Spotify Embed: DNN 8: Computer Vision and Machine Learning Research, Super SloMo | Varun Jampani" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed-podcast/episode/2V4omMjSSGADPqmWgQ89DK"></iframe></figure><p>In this episode, I interview Varun Jampani, who is a Research Scientist at Google Research. You might recognise him from the renowned Super SloMo paper. His work lies at the intersection of Computer Vision and Machine Learning. His main focus is to leverage machine learning techniques for better inference in</p>]]></description><link>http://localhost:2368/dnn-8/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5efdd15afc2ea1b167fe821c</guid><category><![CDATA[Computer Vision]]></category><category><![CDATA[Deep Learning]]></category><category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Mukul Khanna]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 12:22:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2020/07/Podcast-thumbnails.009.jpeg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><iframe width="100%" height="232" allowtransparency="true" frameborder="0" allow="encrypted-media" title="Spotify Embed: DNN 8: Computer Vision and Machine Learning Research, Super SloMo | Varun Jampani" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed-podcast/episode/2V4omMjSSGADPqmWgQ89DK"></iframe></figure><img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2020/07/Podcast-thumbnails.009.jpeg" alt="DNN 8: Computer Vision & ML Research, Super SloMo // Varun Jampani"><p>In this episode, I interview Varun Jampani, who is a Research Scientist at Google Research. You might recognise him from the renowned Super SloMo paper. His work lies at the intersection of Computer Vision and Machine Learning. His main focus is to leverage machine learning techniques for better inference in computer vision models.</p><p>Prior to joining Google, he was a research scientist at NVIDIA.He completed his PhD at the Max-Planck Institute (MPI) for Intelligent Systems. He is also a IIIT Hyderabad alum, where he did his Bachelor's and Master's.</p><p>In this episode we talk about his journey — from his Bachelor's and Masters at IIIT Hyderabad to his PhD at MPI, about how his research has shaped over the years, about his focus on always asking good research questions and tackling fundamental problems in Computer Vision as a whole. We also talk about the SuperSloMo paper, about how it started, the key design decisions that were taken and the challenges faced in the process. If there's one thing that you are likely to take away from this conversation, it is the importance of asking good research questions and letting that drive your learning and research.</p><p>Links: <a href="https://youtu.be/05fGL5jEH5I">Youtube</a> / <a href="https://tinyurl.com/ycudgfse">Anchor.fm</a> / <a href="https://tinyurl.com/y8w7tkhf">Apple Podcasts</a> / <a href="https://tinyurl.com/y7u98d7m">Spotify</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[DNN 3: Data Science on the Web, Mozilla, Matplotlib, Py-odide // Mike Droettboom]]></title><description><![CDATA[<figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><iframe width="100%" height="232" allowtransparency="true" frameborder="0" allow="encrypted-media" title="Spotify Embed: DNN 3: Data Science in Music, Astronomy &amp; Telemetry | Matplotlib, Mozilla &amp; Pyodide | Michael Droettboom " src="https://open.spotify.com/embed-podcast/episode/7aZdMbwIxYfgKpKLxmMRsV"></iframe></figure><p>In the third episode of Deep Neural Notebooks, I talk with Michael Droettboom, from Mozilla.</p><p>Michael is a Staff Data Engineer at Mozilla, where he works on managing the telemetry from Mozilla products, that can be used for improving the user experience and the product itself, while respecting data privacy</p>]]></description><link>http://localhost:2368/dnn-3-data-science-on-the-web-mozilla-matplotlib-pyodide-mike-droettboom/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5efdd055fc2ea1b167fe81ff</guid><category><![CDATA[Open Source]]></category><category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category><category><![CDATA[Web]]></category><category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Mukul Khanna]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 12:18:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2020/07/Podcast-thumbnails.003.jpeg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><iframe width="100%" height="232" allowtransparency="true" frameborder="0" allow="encrypted-media" title="Spotify Embed: DNN 3: Data Science in Music, Astronomy &amp; Telemetry | Matplotlib, Mozilla &amp; Pyodide | Michael Droettboom " src="https://open.spotify.com/embed-podcast/episode/7aZdMbwIxYfgKpKLxmMRsV"></iframe></figure><img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2020/07/Podcast-thumbnails.003.jpeg" alt="DNN 3: Data Science on the Web, Mozilla, Matplotlib, Py-odide // Mike Droettboom"><p>In the third episode of Deep Neural Notebooks, I talk with Michael Droettboom, from Mozilla.</p><p>Michael is a Staff Data Engineer at Mozilla, where he works on managing the telemetry from Mozilla products, that can be used for improving the user experience and the product itself, while respecting data privacy and making sure that instead of snarfing it all up, only the absolutely minimal data is gathered from the user. He specializes in imaging and data: sheet music, scientific visualization, astronomy, biomedical data and software telemetry. He started his Open Source journey around 2007, contributing to Matplotlib, while he was a Senior Computer Scientist at the Space Telescope Science Institute. He later went on to become a lead developer of Matplotlib, carrying on the vision of Matplotlib’s original author, John Hunter.</p><p>In this episode, we talk about his beginnings - his education in Computers’ and Music, his experience in Astronomy, working at the Space Telescope Science Institute and how he got into contributing to Open Source for Matplotlib. We also talk about his role at Mozilla, the importance of data privacy and the amazing project that he is currently working on - Pyodide, an Open Source tool to empower Data Science in the Browser. Michael also shares some advice for beginners trying to get into Data Science and communities just starting out with Open Source software.</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>Links: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z6P0O99QWGE">Youtube</a> / <a href="https://anchor.fm/deep-neural-notebooks/episodes/DNN-3-Data-Science-in-Music--Astronomy--Optics--Telemetry--Matplotlib--Mozilla--Pyodide--Michael-Droettboom-e9f6p9">Anchor.fm</a> / <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/in/podcast/deep-neural-notebooks/id1488705711?i=1000459277460">Apple Podcasts</a> / <a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/7aZdMbwIxYfgKpKLxmMRsV">Spotify</a></p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown-->]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>